<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<about>
	<title1><![CDATA[]]></title1>
	<title2><![CDATA[]]></title2>
	<title3><![CDATA[RESUME]]></title3>
	<description><![CDATA[<font size="12" face="arial"><p align="justify">FREDERIC GONTIER  |  917 373 0280  |  fred@janvier.com  |  www.janvier.com<br></font><br><font color="#609EDB" size="16">Objective</font><br>Seeking position as interactive flash developer.<br><br><font color="#609EDB" size="16">Skills</font><br>AS 3.0, OOP, Adobe Flash IDE, Flash Develop, TextMate, Flex, Github, GAIA Framework, Greensock Framework, Flint framework, SoundFx framework, Adobe Media Encoder, HandBrake, Flowplayer, FlashEff, Google Analytics, XML, Localized Content, PointRoll, Eye Blaster, Papervision, VRML, Photoshop, Illustrator, MAC/PC.<br><br><font color="#609EDB" size="16">Professional experience</font><br><p align="justify"><font color="#FFFFFF">Flash designer/developer: GlobalWorks.com (New York), 2005 – current.</font><br>Principal flash programmer. My responsibilities are programming of flash website and banners, flash presentations and games, CD-Rom, microsites, video production and encoding.<br>I have created a number of multi-lingual media projects with extensive use of xml, external assets, existing as3 libraries and framework. I have also been working closely with Ruby programmers.</p><br><p><font color="#FFFFFF">Web designer: Freelance (New York), 1999 – 2005.</font><br>Flash animation: Cuervo, American Express, Armani Exchange, IBM Sydney Olympics Kiosk.<br>Web design: Estee Lauder, Gloss, Starweaver.</p><br><p><font color="#FFFFFF">Multimedia designer: LearningWorlds.com (New York), 1998 – 1999.</font><br>Principal designer of multimedia projects including Web design and programming (HTML, DHTML), video editing and online production (Real Video), Flash animation, 3D animation (3DStudio MAX) and virtual worlds (VRML).</p><br><p><font color="#FFFFFF">Web designer: Freelance (New York), 1996 – 1998.</font><br>Web design and programming: Grey Interactive. Invisible Ink. The Thinking Media.<br>VRML: Cube3 Production, BRS Architectes, Gertrude Stein Repertory Theatre.<br>3D animation: The Producers, Oslo.<br>Graphic design: Netcast Communication Corp.</p><br><p><font color="#FFFFFF">Product designer: Alain Carre Design, Design Spheres, I.D.A. (Paris), 1989 – 1995.</font><br>Design of industrial machines, medical equipment and consumer products from concept through production. Development of CAD department.</p><br><p><font color="#609EDB" size="16">Education</font></p><p>Diplome Design Industriel (Master of Arts in Industrial Design) Ecole Nationale Superieure des Arts Decoratifs, Paris, 1989.</p><p>BTS Design Industriel (Bachelor of Arts in Industrial Design) Ecole Nationale Superieure des Arts Appliques et Metiers d'Arts, Paris, 1987.</p><br><p><font color="#609EDB" size="16">Misc.</font></p><p>Languages: English / French / basic Russian. American citizen. Sailing. Flash coders NY.<br>References and URLs available upon request</p></font><br><br><p>Download <font color='#609EDB'><a href="work/Frederic_Gontier.pdf" target="_new"> PDF</a></font></p>]]></description>
</about>




