<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<bioList>
	<bio bioName="Kristin Andreotes" title="Project Director">As Project Director at Protobrand, Kristin leads client initiatives through strategic analysis and development, research analysis, competitive audits, client relations, and creative development. She has managed such clients as RSA Security, Dunkin’ Brands, Vertis Communications, Leerink Swann, Houghton Mifflin, Symmons Industries and PTC. Kristin also helps spearhead digital media projects for Protobrand including user design interface and information architecture.
Kristin received a degree in Business Administration from Villanova, graduating cum laude with a major in Marketing and a minor in Humanities/Fine Arts.  Prior to working at Protobrand she obtained extensive experience in marketing, communications, and advertising, with clients such as Eagle National Bank, Malvern Federal Savings Bank, The Melrose Hotel, Mohonk Mountain House, and LaSalle University.   
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Anders Bengtsson" title="Ph.D. / Project Director">Anders is an expert in strategic brand management, specializing in strategy development, cultural branding principles and consumer brand relationship management. He has experience from consulting with leading international companies on their branding strategies, including clients such as Dunkin’ Brands, PPR, Orifarm, and House of Prince.
Before joining Protobrand, Anders spent over ten years in academia conducting research and teaching in brand management and consumer behavior. He has written extensively on the role of brands as important agents of consumer culture. Consumers as well as organizations buy brands for what they do but more importantly for what they mean. They enter relationship with brands and use them to construct individual and collective identities. The brand as an important symbol of meaning has been a common theme in his writings which have appeared in books and numerous journals including Consumption, Markets and Culture and Journal of Product and Brand Management. Anders received his M.S. and Ph.D. in Marketing from Lund University, Sweden.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Jon Craine" title="Creative Director">Jon Craine brings a rich, diverse creative portfolio and record of accomplishment as Creative Director at Protobrand. Admired for his original approach to design, Jon had left a mark of his special talents across the international corporate landscape for companies including Lenovo and Samsung.
Previously, Jon was a Managing Director of Devine & Pearson’s  Design and Branding business unit, successfully creating identity programs for Audax Group, Design Continuum, Johnson & Johnson, Georgia Pacific, Siemens and Thomson Financial. Before that, Jon served for ten years as the worldwide director of design for the Polaroid Corporation, responsible for developing a new global corporate identity. Earlier, Jon was also a principal designer at IBM.
Jon Craine’s name is associated with many familiar, award-winning identity programs, trademarks, corporate logos and brand names. His work has been selected for the Permanent Collections of the Museum of Modern Art in New York, museums in Germany and Finland, and the 45th International Design Conference in Aspen. His work has appeared in such publications as Print, Communication Arts, Graphis, and Domus.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Ryan Coan" title="Director of Business Development">As Director of Business Development, Ryan leads global business development initiatives for Protobrand. In this role in the Boston Office, Ryan works closely with companies to help them understand how their brand might be optimized through the various services offered by Protobrand. Further, based on the individual needs of companies, Ryan helps build the appropriate team to solve specific branding issues, from naming to design to research. Ryan has played a key role in establishing working relationships with many of Protobrand’s flagship clients.
Prior to working at Protobrand, Ryan founded a leading events marketing and promotions company, Pulse Entertainment, based in Florida. Over time, Pulse Entertainment became the hub of a network of eight entertainment and promotions organizations. Pulse was the latest of several successful entertainment and promotions brands lead by Ryan including, Entourage Entertainment. Ryan's experience in this field provides a valuable perspective to clients who benefit from understanding the role of orchestration and production value in the elevation of their brand image.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Steven Cotroneo" title="Interactive Designer">An award winning motion, web, and print designer with 10 years experience in helping diverse businesses of all sizes and dimensions. Steven has an extensive client list and has developed award winning designs solutions for such companies as FLIR systems (a worldwide leader in infrared), Dell, HP, EMC, Comcast, the Dallas Cowboys, Ford, and SAP.
Excelling in Multimedia design, Steven specializes in creating custom built Flash applications, Flash animations, and website designs. Steven has a unique ability to understand his client’s objectives and uses his knowledge of technology to translate that vision into creative designs that meet his client’s objectives.
	</bio>	
	<bio bioName="Bob Curry" title="Advertising">Bob Curry's creative prowess as an art director and creative director has been well recognized throughout the New England advertising community. His ability to translate a client's marketing objectives into clear, memorable visual messages has brought him national recognition and more than 150 awards in the most prestigious competitions in our industry: The One Show, Communication Arts, CLIO Awards, ANDY, New York Art Directors, and New England's Hatch Awards. 
Previously, Bob was senior Vice President/Associate Creative Director at Houston Effler & Partners, with responsibilities for Bay Bank, the Massachusetts Office of Travel & Tourism, McCain's Foods, BASF, Grossman's, Sonesta Hotels, Boston-Bermuda Cruising, Ltd., Howard Johnson's Motor Lodges, Ocean Escapes, Copley Plaza Hotel, Bay State Cruise Lines, and Business Express.
Later, as a Senior Vice President/Associate Creative Director at Hill Holliday Connors Cosmopulos, he worked on Irish Tourist Board, Wang, Spalding Golf, Ocean Spray, and The New England Ford Dealers. Bob was also a partner at Welch, Currier, Curry & Anderson.
In 1993, Bob co-founded Wallwork Curry McKenna, a full-service marketing agency representing leading companies nationwide, where he worked with such clients as Steinway & Sons, New England Telephone, Blue Cross and Blue Shield, John Hancock, Brunswick Golf, and The Boston Globe. Bob is a graduate of Boston?s Museum School of Fine Arts.
	</bio>	
	<bio bioName="Minko T. Dimov" title="Creative Director and Information Architect">For over fifteen years, Minko has been a creative presence in the field of graphic design. An award-winning creative director, Minko specializes in identity and interactive design projects for a wide spectrum of corporate clients such as Dunkin Donuts, Synventive Solutions, MobileQ, Houghton Mifflin, Little, Brown & Co., Vertis Communications, Addison-Wesley/Pearson Education, and International Data Group (IDG). 
His work has been featured in several communications and design publications, including Graphis Magazine. His extensive intercultural experience provides a style that brings to life a deep understanding of cultural discourse and conceptual power within the design process. For Minko, good design is not merely an aesthetic, but a visually engaging solution that pierces through “media noise” to solve complex business issues. 
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Fred Gontier" title="Designer">Frederic has over ten years experience in web design, flash  animation and programming. As a professional web designer, he has developed creative solutions for brands such as Estee Lauder, Cuervo, American Express, Armani Exchange, DirecTV, Ernst & Young, Avaya, Comcast.
Prior to working in web design, Frederic was a product designer in Paris.
Frederic excels in developing dynamic Flash website using XML programming for fast and easy updates. This technology allows the display of multilanguage websites by using the same core flash file and feeding it with external content files. Frederic is also skilled in motion graphics, video and audio production and incorporates these multimedia elements into his sites and projects. 
Frederic also works on experimental sites with artists and photographers, designing open sites that display their portfolios using clean design and technology that can be easily updated.
	</bio>	
	<bio bioName="Philip B. Granof" title="Founding Partner">With over 20 years of experience, Phil is an industry leader in integrated communications and branding systems. He has extensive experience in the areas of positioning, corporate identification, brand portfolio optimization, brand equity evaluation, marketing communications and implementation.
Prior to his co-founding of Protobrand, Phil was a senior partner at Anspach Grossman Portugal (now Enterprise IG) and Lippincott Mercer – in which he managed corporate and brand identity programs for national and multinational clients such as American Express, BOC Gases, Citibank, Deloitte, General Foods, Hardee’s, Hershey’s, IBM, MasterCard, Sprint, RadioShack, and Texaco. Phil’s brand strategy for Deloitte led to the achievement of the 2000 Silver Effie Award for Services Marketing. Phil began his career at Ogilvy & Mather in New York. 
Phil has an M.B.A. from Dartmouth College’s Tuck School of Business, where he has lectured on issues of Branding and Marketing, and a B.A. from UC Berkeley where he graduated summa cum laude.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Ellen Hoffman" title="Research Director">Ellen Hoffman brings expertise in market research and project management to her role as Director of Market Research. Ellen’s background includes 20+ years of experience in marketing intelligence and market research across a wide range of clients and industries.  She has strong credentials in branding research, advertising effectiveness, customer satisfaction, strategic positioning and messaging, and product development.
Prior to joining Protobrand, Ellen directed all Market Intelligence for the $1-Billion Software division of IBM, and spearheaded the design and implementation of quantitative and qualitative research for Lotus Development. 
Ellen has held senior research positions at Ocean Spray, and the prestigious ad agencies Grey Advertising, BBDO Worldwide and Ogilvy & Mather in New York City. 
Ellen has led marketing efforts across all industries sectors including technology, consumer package goods, financial services, retail, fashion, healthcare and travel and tourism. She has worked with a multitude of clients including Proctor & Gamble, General Foods, Gillette, Blue Cross/Blue Shield, McKesson and Bank of America.
	</bio>	
	<bio bioName="Roni Jordan" title="Media Director">Roni has been a media consultant for the past 17 years and previously managed the media departments of some of the most creatively acclaimed ad agencies in Boston and Providence. 
Her strategies encompass the full spectrum of media solutions, both traditional and new, and always challenge the media to exceed their usual limits in sales and service.
Her strong and lasting relationships with major media companies provide the clout and the key to significant savings and priority treatment for clients.
She has directed media activities for clients such as Textron Systems, Lendia, Aubuchon Hardware, Lotus Development, Shawmut Bank, Spalding Golf Clubs, American Tourister, Etonic Footwear, and Blue Cross/Blue Shield of Rhode Island.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Marty Kenney" title="Promotions and Merchandising">Marty Kenney has more than twenty years of corporate experience; having held senior level marketing positions with several medium to large-size, publicly owned retail chains.  His last corporate position was Director of Marketing and Advertising for Bradlees in Braintree, Massachusetts.  
Responsibilities included creative direction, production, store signing, advertising agency direction, sales promotion, budget development, and print media placement for the $2 billion retail chain with 140 locations throughout the northeast.  
In this capacity, Marty managed an organization of 54 employees and an annual budget of $60 million.  Among his accomplishments, Marty oversaw the implementation of Bradlees’ first electronic publishing system, saving the company over $2 million annually and cutting lead times dramatically.  Among the clients Marty has served in the promotion industry are Houghton Mifflin, Verizon, CVS/Pharmacy, Raytheon Company, Atari, Agfa Corporation, iRobot, Cytyc Corporation and Caritas Christi Healthcare. Marty is a graduate of the University of Massachusetts in Amherst with a BA in Fine Art; and he has an MBA in Marketing from Babson College.  
	</bio>	
<!--	<bio bioName="Paul Kroner" title="Designer">Paul has been an award winning graphic designer in New England for over 20 years. For the past seven years Paul has owned and operated an independent design studio located in Somerville, MA.
Prior to starting Kroner Design in 1998, Paul was a creative director for a nationally-know marketing communication design firm in Andover, MA where some of his client included Hewlett-Packard, The Boston Pops, Emerson College, and Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary.
Paul creates powerful design solutions for companies ranging from high technology to travel and educational organizations. He specializes in identity and brand development, marketing collateral, and Web site design. 
Paul excels at the creative work and invests a considerable amount of time and energy to understand the business strategy that each piece of design must achieve. With over twenty years experience, he knows how to make it look great, meet the communication goals and objectives, and do both within budget and on-time. 
	</bio>  -->
	<bio bioName="Yuly Mekler" title="Creative Director">Yuly is an accomplished, award-winning creative director whose design work is both provocative and conceptual. He also has over twenty-five years of experience in graphic and architectural design, creation, implementation, and management of global corporate identity programs across a full-range of media, from print to web-based applications, to packaging and environmental graphics. 
Clients include IBM, Lotus Development, Cisco Systems, Harvard Pilgrim Healthcare, RSA Security, UMASS, MIT, White Mountain, Agroport, Luxe Beauty, Thomson Learning, Earth Footwear, Modellista, and Vertis Communications.
Yuly holds a B.A. and an M.A. from Academy of Civil Engineering in Saint Petersburg, Russia and an M.F.A. in Design from Massachusetts College of Art.
	</bio>	
	<bio bioName="Stephen Melanson" title="Brand Training Director">Stephen Melanson has twenty-three years experience in brand communications, marketing, and sales in several industry sectors including management consulting, software, telecommunications, consumer service, and training. His clients include Spaulding & Slye, Conquest Partners, Inc.,Comsys Technical Services, AllSet Services, Microsoft, Xerox, US Army Corps / Engineers, Dunkin Donuts, Amazon.com, and MRO Software. Stephen’s background also includes being a trained psychotherapist. 
As a branding consultant, with expertise in direct communications, Stephen’s “verbal branding” instruction is truly unique in the branding world. Delivered in a classroom setting, it provides a high impact finishing element that helps fulfill a brands’ potential, immediately improving the productivity of every conversation clients have with prospects and clients.
While helping thousands of individuals with external communications, this verbal application has also promoted a “living the brand” culture internally for clients so awareness, understanding, and confidence in the brand are enhanced.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Bob Robbins" title="Founding Partner">Bob has spent thirty years launching new companies and brands as well as transforming large multinational companies. He has helped numerous clients worldwide to achieve a strategic business advantage while optimizing the value of their brand equity. He lends his business acumen to all engagements especially those that require a strong understanding of the interplay between brand, business and culture. He has worked with CEO’s and executive teams for global consumer and business-to-business companies including Abbott Laboratories, Thomson Corporation, GE, Staples, Dupont, NEC, Unilever, American Express, Kraft Foods, Exelon Energy, Partners Healthcare, RSA Security, Merrill Lynch, and Clarks of England. His activities with these companies span from vision and value proposition development to brand equity measurement and experience innovation.
Prior to Co-founding Protobrand, Bob served as Chief Operating Officer of BrandEquity International and Chief Branding Officer of Nexient Corporation. He has held senior management positions with BBDO Worldwide, Ogilvy & Mather and J.C. Penney. As author and lecturer, he has been featured in leading communications and business publications including Marketing News, Brand Marketing, Sales and Marketing Magazine and Design Management Institute’s Bulletin. He is a frequent speaker at leading industry events and conferences including Interbev, Design Management Institute, Massport, The International Mass Retailing Federation, Inc. Magazine’s Executive Conference Series, and The Institute for International Research. Bob is a recipient of the highly coveted Grand EFFIE award for his work on the GE brand campaign “We Bring Good Things To Life”. 
	</bio>	
	<bio bioName="Bob Russell" title="Creative Director">As Creative Director at Protobrand, Bob Russell specializes in harmonizing and integrating multiple design disciplines including naming, identity, signage, architecture, interior environments, merchandising, packaging, retail brands, web and communications, to create powerful single-minded, emotionally driven brands. Bob leads design strategy and creative output across many business sectors, including consumer goods, financial services, telecommunications, technology, health and beauty, sports and leisure, spirits and hospitality.
Bob has directed strategic design initiatives for clients including RSA Security, Authoria, Allied Domecq, Nestle, Charles River Ventures, Quaker Oats, Bell Mobility, Fidelity Investments, The Toronto Raptors and Miami Heat basketball teams, Maxfli Golf, Groove Networks and Mercator Software.
Before joining Protobrand, Bob lead award-winning creative and design firms for the past three decades. His creative work and writings on the use of design as a strategic tool has been widely published internationally.
	</bio>
	<bio bioName="Jonathan Stark" title="Photographer">Jonathan Stark is a photographer and artist bringing a distinct visual and emotional perspective to his work. With clients spanning from software developers to human service providers Jonathan has delivered a visual product that resonates with the emotional content of his clients’ messages.  Jonathan also directed brand-imaging programs for such clients as Houghton Mifflin, Millipore, Microlis, Polaroid, Dun & Bradstreet, Berklee School of Music, and Arkwright Insurance.
Jonathan studied photography at the State University of New York at Binghamton and at the New England School of Photography. While living in Paris in 1994, he found the visual magic that captured Willy Ronis, Brassai, and Cartier-Bresson, and often exhibited this work at major shows including “Visages et Paysages,” at the French Library and Cultural Center in 2002. Jonathan’s recent photographs focus on his unabashed enchantment with the human face, form and the interactions and emotions that define us.
	</bio>	
</bioList>
